Finding Aid for the Edgar Hill Duncan Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Convention and Individuality in Chaucer’s Complaint (Box 13)
- Notes on Chaucer: Earlier or Minor Poems (Box 13)
- A Note on Chaucer’s Adam (Box 13)
- Chaucer. The Hous of Fame (Box 13)
- The Plimpton Chaucer and Other Problems... (Box 13)
- The Parlement of Foules (Box 13)
- [review of] Chapters on Chaucer (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Eight Years’ Sickness (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s “Shapen Was My Sherte” (Box 13)
- Chaucer and Alchemy (Box 13)
- The Miniatures of the Ellesmere Chaucer (Box 13)
- The ’Troilus’ Frontispiece (Box 13)
- The Times of Edward the Black Prince.... (Box 13)
- The Sea-Battle in Chaucer’s “Legend of Cleopatra” (Box 13)
- Chaucer in Tartary (Box 13)
- Arms and Armor in Chaucer (Box 13)
- Chaucer and the Auchinleck MS... (Box 13)
- [review] The Equatorie of the Planetis... (Box 13)
- “Joye After Woe” in The Knight’s Tale (Box 13)
- St’ Cecilia’s Garlands and Their Roman Origin (Box 13)
- The Order of the Canterbury Tales (Box 13)
- “Homicide” in The Parson’s Tale (Box 13)
- Death and Old Age in The Pardoner’s Tale (Box 13)
- Satire in Sir Thopas (Box 13)
- The Marriage Group in The Canterbury Tales (Box 13)
- Was Robyn the Miller’s Youth Misspent? (Box 13)
- Symkyn Koude “Turne Coppes”:... (Box 13)
- Chaucer and Isidore on Why Men Marry (Box 13)
- What Was Chaucer’s Aim in The Knight’s Tale (Box 13)
- Did Chaucer Rearrange the Clerk’s Envoy? (Box 13)
- A Note on Chaucer and the Ploicritus of John... (Box 13)
- Susannah and the Merchant’s Tale (Box 13)
- Scribal Errors in Manly and Rickert’s Text (Box 13)
- The Sources of Chaucer’s Constance and Thisbe (Box 13)
- Narrator’s Points of View in the Portrait-Sketches (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Pardoner’s Tale and Flanders (Box 13)
- The Malady of Chaucer’s Summoner (Box 13)
- More About Chaucer’s Wife of Bath (Box 13)
- Canon’s Yeoman’s Prologue (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Self-Portrait and Dante’s (Box 13)
- [letter to the editor of The Listener] (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Hell: A Study in Mediaeval Convention (Box 13)
- Chaucer and the Great Italian Writers of the Trecento (Box 13)
- Chaucer and the Visconti Libraries (Box 13)
- The Art of Geoffrey Chaucer (Box 13)
- Chaucer Redivivus or Bread and Milk for Babes (Box 13)
- The Importance of Manuscripts for the Study of Medieval Education (Box 13)
- Chaucer and Mediaeval Romance (Box 13)
- Geoffrey Chaucer (Box 13)
- Chaucer: A Critical Appreciation (Box 13)
- [combined: two reprints from] University of Toronto Quarterly (Box 13)
- Chaucer Redivivus or Bread and Milk for Babes (Box 13)
- Rhetorical Balance in Chaucer’s Poetry (Box 13)
- Chaucer and the Common People (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Use of the Vulgate (Box 13)
- On Rereading Chaucer (Box 13)
- Echoes of the Anathema in Chaucer (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Collquial English... (Box 13)
- [review of] Chaucer and the Fifteenth Century (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Self-Portrait and Dante’s (Box 13)
- Chaucer and Dante (Box 13)
- Bycorne-Bygorne, Husband of Chichevache (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Retractions (Box 13)
- The Moralité of the Nun’s Priest’s Sermon (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Prioress: Her Green Gauds (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Knight’s Tale (Box 13)
- [sheet from Williams Alumni Review] (Box 13)
- [sheet from New College Record] (Box 13)
- Young Hugh of Lincoln and Chaucer’s “The Prioress’s (Box 13)
- The MS Fitzwilliam: An Examination.... (Box 13)
- The Dangerous Theme of the Pardoner (Box 13)
- The Development of The Canterbury Tales (Box 13)
- The Evolution of the Canterbury “Marriage Group” (Box 13)
- The Twenty-Nine Pilgrims and the Three Priests (Box 13)
- The Summoner’s “Psalm of Davit” (Box 13)
- The Social Status of Chaucer’s Franklin (Box 13)
- St. Augustine and the Parson’s Tale (Box 13)
- Satire in Sir Thopas (Box 13)
- [review of] Sources and Analogues of Chaucer’s... (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Man of Law’s Tale and Constance... (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s MS of Petrarch’s Version of the Griselda (Box 13)
- Sampson, David, and Salomon in the Parson’s Tale (Box 13)
- The Unity of Chaucer’s Manciple Fragment (Box 13)
- The Man of Law’s Head-link and the Prologue... (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Merchant’s Tale and Courtly Love (Box 13)
- Sampson, David, and Salomon in the Parson’s Tale (Box 13)
- On the Order of the Canterbury Tales: Caxton’s... (Box 13)
- The “Secree of Secrees” of Chaucer’s Canon’s Yeoman (Box 13)
- The Source of Chaucer’s Melibeus (Box 13)
- Chaucer on Preachers and Preaching (Box 13)
- Three Notes on the Text of the Canterbury Tales (Box 13)
- Cicero On Parnassus (Box 13)
- The Convent of Chaucer’s Prioress... (Box 13)
- The Five Craftsmen (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Sir Thopas (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Shipman’s Tale ... (Box 13)
- Was Chaucer a Laodicean? (Box 13)
- An Augustinian Interpretation of Chaucer’s Pardoner (Box 13)
- [a combined review of 2 Chaucer volumes] (Box 13)
- The Nine-Syllabled Pentameter Line... (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Originality in the Nun’s Priest’s Tale (Box 13)
- The Mediaeval-Modern Conflict in Chaucer’s Poetry (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Prose Rhythms (Box 13)
- The Two Petros in the “Monkes Tale” (Box 13)
- The Tale of Melibeus (Box 13)
- A Note on Chaucer’s Use of Aristotelian Psychology (Box 13)
- The Man of Law’s Head-Link... (Box 13)
- Chaucer and Dante’s Convivio (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Pardoner’s Tale and Flanders (Box 13)
- Beginning the Board in Prussia (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Squire (Box 13)
- Simple and Coy: A Note... (Box 13)
- The Prioress’s Oath (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Madame Eglantine (Box 13)
- •Seint Julian He Was’ (Box 13)
- Bretherhed in Chaucer’s Prolog (Box 13)
- A Thirteenth Century Chaucerian Analogue (Box 13)
- The Duration of Canterbury Pilgrimage (Box 13)
- The Progress of Chaucer’s Pardoner (Box 13)
- Idiom of Popular Poetry in the Miller’s Tale (Box 13)
- Illustrations of Chaucer. Drawn Chiefly... (Box 13)
- Dramatic Irony (Box 13)
- Chaucer The Works (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Doctrine of Kings and Tyrants (Box 13)
- The Mediaeval-Modern Conflict in Chaucer’s Poetry (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s ’Good Ear’ (Box 13)
- Chaucer and the Cambridge Edition (Box 13)
- Was Chaucer a Laodicean? (Box 13)
- Chaucer: Selected References (Box 13)
- Some Reflections On Chaucer’s ’Art Poetical’ (Box 13)
- Blanche, Duchess of Lancaster (Box 13)
- Notes on Chaucer: The Canterbury Tales (Box 13)
- The Place of Group F in the Canterbury Chronology (Box 13)
- Manly’s Conception of the Early History of the Canterbury Tales (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s ’Holt and Heeth’ (Box 13)
- The Original Teller of the Merchant’s Tale (Box 13)
- Chaucer and the Miroir de Mariage (Box 13)
- The Mediaeval Setting of Chaucer’s Monk’s Tale (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Bed’s Head (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s “Shipman’s Tale” in Modern Dress (Box 13)
- Narrator’s Points of View in the Portrait-Sketches. The Fifteenth-Century Editors of the Canterbury Tales (Box 13)
- Chaucer the Pilgrim (Box 13)
- Satire in Sir Thopas (Box 13)
- Autobiographical Aspects of Chaucer’s Franklin (Box 13)
- Chaucer Borrowing from Himself (Box 13)
- “Whan He His Papir Soghte” (Box 13)
- The Debate on Marriage in the Canterbury Tales (Box 13)
- Chaucer and the Pillars of Hercules (Box 13)
- The Original Teller of the Merchant’s Tale (Box 13)
- Two Chaucer Notes, Three Notes on the Knight’s Tale (Box 13)
- The Mediaeval Setting of Chaucer’s Monk’s Tale (Box 13)
- The Source of Chaucer’s Melibeus (Box 13)
- The Arming of Sir Thopas (Box 13)
- Was Chaucer’s Knight’s Tale Extensively Revised... (Box 13)
- The Marital Dilemma in the Wife of Bath’s Tale (Box 13)
- Knight’s Tale (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Nun’s Priest Again (Box 13)
- Is the Manciple’s Tale a Success? (Box 13)
- The Mediaeval Loveday (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s “Text That Seith That Hunters Ben Nat Hooly Men” (Box 13)
- [review of] Sources and Analgues of Chaucer’s.... (Box 13)
- Notes on the Cardigan Chaucer Manuscript (Box 13)
- A Review of English Literature vol 1 no 3 (Box 13)
- A Chaucer Scribe’s Concern with Page Format Some Chaucer Allusions by Sir Edward Coke (Box 13)
- Arcite’s Illness and Vincent of Beauvais (Box 13)
- The Social Status of Chaucer’s Franklin (Box 13)
- Journal of English and German Philology XXIV, 4 (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Prioress’ Tale: An Early Analogue (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s ’Sad’ Merchant (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Shipman’s Tale (Box 13)
- The Order of the Canterbury Tales.... (Box 13)
- Two Chaucer Notes... (Box 13)
- Chaucerian Minutiae (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Satire of the Pardoner (Box 13)
- Troilus and Pilgrims in Wartime (Box 13)
- Chaucer and Seneca (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Doctor of Phisyk (Box 13)
- “By My Fader Soule” (Box 13)
- [review of] The Text of the Canterbury Tales (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Shipman’s Tale and Sercambi (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Miller’s Tale (Box 13)
- The Meaning of Chaucer’s Prologue to “Sir Thopas” (Box 13)
- England’s Discovery of the Decameron (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Plowman and the Contemporary English Peasant (Box 13)
- The Political Meaning of Chaucer’s Tale of Melibee (Box 13)
- The Clerk’s Tale As a Possible Source for Pandosto (Box 13)
- Another Analogue for the Violation... (Box 13)
- Is the Manciple’s Tale a Success? (Box 13)
- On the Significance of Hengwrt’s Change of Ink in The Merchant’s Tale (Box 13)
- The Genre of Chaucer’s Squire’s Tale (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Originality in the Nun’s Priest’s Tale Author’s Revision in Block C of the Canterbury Tales (Box 13)
- A Chapter of the Manuscript History of the Canterbury Tales (Box 13)
- The Loveres Maladye of Hereos (Box 13)
- Chaucer and the Ovide Moralise... (Box 13)
- A Note on Chaucer’s Use of Aristotelian Psychology (Box 13)
- Calchas in the Early Versions of the Troilus Story (Box 13)
- [various reviews reprinted from Modern Language Notes] (Box 13)
- The People in Chaucer’s Troilus (Box 13)
- Hymselven Lik a Pilgrym to Desguise (Box 13)
- Aspects of the Relationship of Boccaccio’s... (Box 13)
- Thebes, Troy, Criseyde, and Pandarus... (Box 13)
- On the Tradition of Troilus’s Vision... (Box 13)
- Chaucer and Le Roman de Troyle et de Criseida (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Use of the Teseida (Box 13)
- A Note on Chaucer’s Lollius (Box 13)
- The Domestic Background of Troilus and Criseyde (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s “Troilus and Criseyde” As Romance (Box 13)
- Two Notes on Chaucer’s Troilus (Box 13)
- Ε L H A Journal of English Literary History v 19, n 1 (Box 13)
- Troilus on Determinism (Box 13)
- Boethius’ Influence on Chaucer’s Troilus (Box 13)
- The Story of Troilus and Briseida in the Laud Troy-Book (Box 13)
- Destiny in Chaucer’s Troilus (Box 13)
- A Planetary Date for Chaucer’s Troilus (Box 13)
- Salvatore Battaglia’s Edition of the Teseida (Box 13)
- A Note on Chaucer’s Lollius (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s “Vitremyte” (Box 13)
- Boethius’ Influence on Chaucer’s Troilus (Box 13)
- Defense of Criseyde (Box 13)
- A Geographical Problem in Troilus and Criseyde (Box 13)
- The Function of the Proverbial Monitory Elements... (Box 13)
- Thomas Chaucer (Box 13)
- Why Was Chaucer Sent to Milan in 1378? (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Sovereign Lady (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Eight Years’ Sickness (Box 13)
- The Meaning of Chaucer’s Envoy to Scogan (Box 13)
- Chaucer and Wyclif (Box 13)
- The New Chaucer Item (Box 13)
- The Emerging Biography of a Poet (Box 13)
- Thomas Chaucer, One Man or Two? (Box 13)
- New Life-Records of Chaucer Addendum (Box 13)
- Chaucer and Aldgate (Box 13)
- Studies in the Life-Records of Chaucer (Box 13)
- The Duration of Chaucer’s Visits to Italy (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s “My Maistre Bukton” (Box 13)
- Messire Otón de Graunson, Chaucer’s Savoyard Friend (Box 13)
- Sir Oton de Graunson — “Flour of Hem that make in Fraunce” (Box 13)
- Geoffrey Chaucer, J.P. and M.P. (Box 13)
- Chaucer and the Earl of Oxford (Box 13)
- Chaucer’s Eight Years’ Sickness (Box 13)
- Chaucer and Graunson: The Valentine Tradition (Box 13)
- Sir Lewis Clifford’s French Mission of, 1391 (Box 13)
- Chaucer and Dame Alice Perrers (Box 13)
- The Route of Chaucer’s First Journey to Italy (Box 13)
- Geoffrey Chaucer, Esq., and Sir John Hawkwood (Box 13)
- Kirk’s Life Records of Thomas Chaucer (Box 13)
- DUNCAN CORRESPONDENCE — OUTGOING (Box 14)
- 1940’s & 50’s (Box 14)
- [sheets between files] (Box 14)
- Sept. 1965 (Box 14)
- [sheets between files] (Box 14)
- 1966 (Box 14)
- August 1966 (Box 14)
- [sheets between files] (Box 14)
- 1967 (Box 14)
- 1968 (Box 14)
- 1969 (Box 14)
- 1970-1975 (Box 14)
- 1976- (Box 14)
- Letters of Recommendation (Box 14)
- (Box 15)
- DUNCAN CORRESPONDENCE — INCOMING A - G (Box 15)
- A - (Box 15)
- Ba - Be (Box 15)
- Bi - Bo (Box 15)
- Br - By (Box 15)
- Caldwell - (Box 15)
- Carruthers - (Box 15)
- Ch - (Box 15)
- D (Box 15)
- Davis, Kenneth Eisenhart, L.P. (Box 15)
- F (Box 15)
- Fulmer, Constance (Box 15)
- G (Box 15)
- (Box 16)
- DUNCAN CORRESPONDENCE — INCOMING H - O (Box 16)
- Ha - Hay (Box 16)
- He - (Box 16)
- I (Box 16)
- J (Box 16)
- K (Box 16)
- Kuniholm (Box 16)
- Lawson (Box 16)
- L (Box 16)
- M (Box 16)
- Mankin, Philip (Box 16)
- Mitchell, Jerome (Box 16)
- N - O (Box 16)
- Kernohan, Donald (Box 16)
- (Box 17)
- DUNCAN CORRESPONDENCE — INCOMING P - Z (Box 17)
- P (except Pittman) (Box 17)
- Pittman (Box 17)
- Pittman (Box 17)
- R - Ri (Box 17)
- Ro - Ru (Box 17)
- [sheets between files] (Box 17)
- S (except Stuart) (Box 17)
- Stuart, Jesse (Box 17)
- T (Box 17)
- U - V (Box 17)
- W (Box 17)
- Want, Cleve (Box 17)
- Wooden, W.W. (Box 17)
- X Y Z (Box 17)
- (Box 18)
- [unlabeled manila envelope] (Box 18)
- [torn legal envelope atop files] Geber Summa (Box 18)
- [legal envelope atop files] Glasgow - Hunterian (Box 18)
- Notes for Intro, on Alchemy & Geber (Box 18)
- Table of Contents and Notes on T C (Box 18)
- For chap, on Alchemy (Box 18)
- For intro. to book 2 # 1 (Box 18)
- [unlabeled] (Box 18)
- My 1971 MLA paper (Box 18)
- Notes re revision of diss. Alchemy -Work Copy Variant Readings Summa Geberi (Box 18)
- work copy variant readings [unlabeled] Geber’s Sum (Box 18)
- # 3 (Box 18)
- # 4 (Box 18)
- The Green Lion (Box 18)
- The Letter of the Sun to the Crescent Moon (Box 18)
- The Mirror of Philosophy (Box 18)
- The Little Golden Book (Box 18)
- A Letter of John Dastin about The Philosopher’s Stone (Box 18)
- Vicio de dono gracie (Box 18)
- Bull Forbidding the Practice of Alchemy (Box 18)
- [unlabeled] (Box 18)
- [sheets between files] (Box 18)
- Geber Summa (Box 18)
- [campus mail manila envelope] Rough Notes Marked Up I - VI (Box 18)
- [campus mail manila envelope unlabeled] [campus mail manila envelope] Notes on L. text [campus mail manila envelope] Russell Translation (Box 18)
- (Box 19)
- [4 large boxes of index cards] (Box 19)
- (Box 20)
- [1 large box of index cards] (Box 20)
- [shoebox of index cards and spiral notebook] (Box 20)
- [box of microfilm] Geber 1525 (Box 20)
- [box w/ 2 rolls microfilm] 1: Summa, 2: Fonds Lat (Box 20)